Sometimes the adventure of a lifetime becomes life itself.
I Dreamed of Africa is a romance, drama, adventure film directed by Hugh Hudson.
Inspired by the true story of indomitable Kuki Gallmann, the film tells of a beautiful and inquisitive woman who had the courage to escape from her
comfortable yet monotonous life in Italy to start anew in the African wilderness with her son, Emanuele, and her new husband, Paolo.
Gallmann faces great danger there but eventually
becomes a celebrated conservationist.
Kuki Gallmann, played by Kim Basinger.
Paolo Gallmann, played by Vincent Perez.
7-Year-Old Emanuele, played by Liam Aiken.
Declan Fielding, played by Daniel Craig.
Franca, played by Eva Marie Saint.
Simon, played by Lance Reddick.
I Dreamed of Africa is a 2000 American biographical-drama film
directed by Hugh Hudson, starring Kim Basinger.
It also stars Vincent Perez, Eva Marie Saint, Garrett
Strommen, Liam Aiken and Daniel Craig.
It is based on the autobiographical novel I Dreamed of Africa by Kuki Gallmann, an
Italian writer who moved to Kenya and became involved in conservation.
It was screened in the Un Certain Regard section
at the 2000 Cannes Film Festival.
This film was both a commercial and critical failure.
The tone is emotional.